hello! Today we will learn expressions used at an alley restaurant in Gamcheon Culture Village.
Do you have any idea what to say at a Korean restaurant?
Once you learn them one by one, you can confidently order from anywhere. LetŐs go together!
As I walked through the alley, I felt hungry. At times like this, we say, ÔIŐm hungry.Ő
ÔBaeŐ means hungry, and ÔIŐm hungryŐ means I need food. Find a delicious restaurant.
There is an order in a restaurant. ÔFindŐ a restaurant, ÔorderŐ, express ÔtasteŐ, ÔcalculateŐ.
Today we will learn these four steps along with expressions appropriate for the situation.
In an unfamiliar neighborhood, you don't know where the food is delicious. Ask someone passing by.
ÔIs there a good restaurant near hereŐ? Please kindly tell me this.
If it's difficult to choose, ask them to choose. ÔIs there a restaurant you can recommend?Ő
ÔRecommendationŐ means selecting something good and telling it to you.
If you're curious about popular food in your neighborhood, ask 'What's famous here?' I ask.
ÔFamousŐ means that many people like it.
If you're curious about what's for sale, ask 'What is this house for sale'? I ask.
ÔSellŐ means selling. You can ask in advance before entering.
If the menu looks appetizing, we say, ÔIt looks delicious.Ő
'-It looks like' means it feels that way when you see it. Come into this restaurant!
When you enter, the clerk asks. ÔHow many are you?Ő ÔHow many people are thereŐ? It means.
Checking the number of guests.
If you're alone, it's 'one person', if you're together, it's 'two people'. ÔMyeongŐ is a word for counting people.
It's more clear if you show the number with your fingers.
When you see an empty seat, do you think, ÔCan I sit here?Ő I ask. Ô-Can I have a babyŐ?
means asking for permission. If you say ÔyesŐ, you can sit down.
Once you sit down, you need a menu. ÔPlease give me the menuŐ.
ÔMenuŐ is a list of food, and ÔpleaseŐ is a polite request.
If you don't know what to choose, ask yourself, 'What's delicious here?' I ask.
You can get recommendations on things that the house is good at.
If you're curious about what's ordered a lot, ask 'What's the popular menu?' I ask.
Popular menu items usually never fail.
If you have trouble choosing, ask the clerk, ŇPlease recommend a menu.Ó
It means ÔPlease choose for me.Ő
Point to food you see for the first time and ask, ÔWhat is this?Ő I ask. ÔThisŐ is ÔThisŐ.
Ask any questions you have.
If you are curious about the material, ask ÔWhat is this made from?Ő I ask.
Be sure to check if there are any ingredients you cannot eat.
The ingredients are usually like this. ÔRiceŐ, ÔmeatŐ, ÔvegetablesŐ, and ÔseafoodŐ like fish.
Most people understand these four things.
If you're curious about the taste, ask 'What does this taste like?' I ask. It's easy to choose if you know the taste in advance.
If you can't eat spicy food, be sure to ask. ÔIs this spicyŐ?
This is a very important question because Korean food is very spicy.
To avoid spicy food, ÔIs there anything that isnŐt spicy?Ő I ask.
ÔAnŐ means ÔnotŐ, that is, it is not spicy.
If you share or are hungry, is it Ôtoo muchŐ? I ask. ÔAmountŐ is the amount of food.
Once you've made your choice, point to it and say 'Please give me this' to finish ordering.
ÔThisŐ is the most commonly used spelling expression.
Also tell me the number. ÔPlease give me one of this and two of that.Ő If it's close, it's 'this', and if it's far, it's 'that'.
If you are thirsty, say, ÔGive me some water.Ő Water is free at Korean restaurants. If you add 'jom', it becomes softer.
The food is here! Before eating, say, ÔI will eat well.Ő
It is an expression of gratitude to the person who made it.
If there aren't enough side dishes, 'Please give me more side dishes.' ÔMoreŐ is addition. Side dishes are usually provided for free.
If you don't have a spoon, 'Please give me chopsticks and a spoon.'
ÔChopsticksŐ means picking up, and ÔspoonŐ means scooping.
If I want to eat more, ÔCan I refill this?Ő ÔRefillŐ means to refill.
Express the taste. If itŐs delicious, itŐs ÔdeliciousŐ! When you raise your thumb, your feelings are conveyed more.
This is a huge compliment to the person who made it.
Spicy taste is ÔspicyŐ, salty taste is ÔsaltyŐ. If you add Ôa littleŐ, it becomes soft Ń Ôa little spicy.Ő
If the taste is sweet, it will be ÔsweetŐ, if the seasoning is weak, it will be ÔblandŐ. Each taste has a different expression.
A clean taste is ÔlightŐ, and a savory taste like sesame oil is ÔsavoryŐ. It's perfect for complimenting the soup.
Taste expression summary!
ÔSpicyŐ, ÔsaltyŐ, ÔsweetŐ, ÔsourŐ, ÔbitterŐ, ÔblandŐ, ÔsavoryŐ,
ÔFeelŐ. You can use it according to the situation.
If you ate it all, you ate well.
Before eating, say, ÔI will eat well,Ő and after eating, say, ÔI ate well.Ő I remember them as a pair.
If you have leftovers, can you please pack the leftovers? ÔCheapŐ means packaging.
When you're done eating, go to the counter and say, 'I'll pay, how much is it?' ÔCalculateŐ means putting a price on it, Ôhow much is it?Ő
is to ask about the price.
If it's a card, 'Can it be a card?' , if it is cash, ÔI will pay in cashŐ. Some small stores only accept cash.
If you need a receipt, say ÔPlease give me a receipt.Ő It's a piece of paper that says how much you paid.
If it was delicious, 'It was really delicious here, I want to come again'! A warm word becomes a good memory.
LetŐs take a look at todayŐs trend. Find, order, taste, checkout. Now you know what words to use in each situation, right?
Well done!
Be sure to use the expressions you learned today at a restaurant. The more you use it, the more natural it becomes.
Next, letŐs learn cafe expressions. hi!